在这个视频中，我们将讨论如何训练这个U-Net神经网络并让它预测噪声。
In this video, we'll discuss how to train this U-Net neural network and get it to predict noise.
我们的目标是让网络预测噪声，真正的任务是让它学习图像上的噪声分布，
So the goal of the neural network is for it to predict noise, and really it learns the distribution of what is noise on the image,
但也要学习什么不是噪声，像是游戏角色的特征。
but also what is not noise, what is sprite likeness, right?
我们的做法是从训练数据中取一个游戏角色，然后给它加噪声。
And so how we do that is that we take a sprite from our training data and we actually add noise to it.
我们给它加噪声，然后让神经网络预测这个噪声。
We add noise to it and we give it to the neural network and we ask the neural network to predict that noise.
然后我们将预测的噪声与实际添加到图像上的噪声进行比较。
And then we compare the predicted noise against the actual noise that was added to that image.
这就是我们计算损失的方式。
And that's how we compute the loss.
然后通过反向传播让神经网络学会更好地预测噪声。
And that backprops through the neural network so that the neural network learns to predict that noise better.
那么如何确定这里的噪声是什么呢？
So how do you determine what this noise here is?
你可以通过时间和采样，给它不同的噪声级别。
You could just go through time and sampling and give it different noise levels.
但在实际训练中，我们不希望神经网络一直观察同一个游戏角色图像。
But realistically in training, we don't want the neural network to be looking at the same sprite all the time.
如果在一个周期内观察不同的游戏角色图像，它会更稳定，更均匀。
It helps it to be more stable if it looks at different sprites across an epoch and it's just more uniform.
所以我们实际上是随机采样一个可能的时间步长，
So actually what we do is we randomly sample what this time step could be.
然后获取相应的噪声级别，
We then get the noise level appropriate to that time step.
添加到图像中，再让神经网络预测。
We add it to this image and then we have the neural network predict it.
然后我们取下一个训练数据中的游戏角色图像。
We take the next sprite image in our training data.
再次随机采样一个时间步长，
We again sample a random time step.
它可能完全不同，就像你在这里看到的。
It could be totally different like you see here.
然后我们把它加到这个游戏角色图像上，再次让神经网络预测添加的噪声。
And then we add it to this sprite image and again we have the neural network predict the noise that was added.
这样就得到了一个更稳定的训练方案。
And this results in a much more stable training scheme.
那么训练实际上是什么样子？
So what does training actually look like?
这是一个巫师帽子图像。
Here is a wizard hat sprite.
这是一个添加了噪声的输入图像。
And here is what a noised input would look like.
当你刚把它放入神经网络时，神经网络还没有真正学会什么是图像。
And when you first put it into the neural network at epoch zero, the neural network hasn't really learned what a sprite is yet.
所以预测的噪声并没有改变输入的样子。
So the predicted noise doesn't quite change what the input looks like.
当它被减去时，实际上就变成了这个，看起来差不多。
And when it's subtracted out, it actually just turns into this which looks about the same.
但到了第31轮时，神经网络对这个图像有了更好的理解。
But by the time you get to epoch 31, the neural network has a better understanding of what this sprite looks like.
然后它预测的噪声就能从这个输入中减去，产生一个看起来像这个巫师帽的图像。
So then it predicts noise that is then subtracted from this input to produce something that does look like this wizard hat sprite.
酷，这是一个样本。
Cool, so that was for one sample.
这是多个不同样本，多个不同图像经过多轮训练的样子。
This is for multiple different samples, multiple different sprites across many epochs and what that looks like.
如你所见，在第一轮训练中，这些模型与我们的目标（游戏角色）还相距甚远。
As you can see in this first epoch, it is quite far from sprites.
但是，到了第32轮，你会发现这些模型已经很像小游戏角色了，即便在那之前，其实也已经有了一些形状。
But by the time you get to epoch 32 here, it looks quite like little video game characters and even before that.
好的，现在我们通过一些代码来了解训练算法。
All right, so now we'll go through the training algorithm with some code.
首先，你需要选择一个训练图像。
So first you want to sample a training image.
这里我们将所有数据加载到数据加载器中，
So here we are loading up all the data into the data loader.
然后将其放入一个进度条，以便我们可以看到它的变化。
We're putting into a progress bar so that we can visualize it.
你可以将这里想象成所有的数据。
But essentially imagine all the data here.
然后我们逐个处理所有的数据样本，
We're then iterating through all of the data samples.
x 在这里表示一个训练图片。
So X here is a training image.
现在我们来看看 x。
So just looking at X now.
在这个循环中，我们会选择一个时间步长 T，
Within this loop, we are sampling a time step T.
它决定了噪声的级别。
And this determines the level of noise.
我们不会遍历所有时间步长，只采样一个时间步长 T。
We're not going through all the time steps, just sampling a time step T.
我们产生一个噪音，
We sample a noise.
然后根据时间步长将这个噪音加到图片上，
We add that noise to the image based on that time step.
然后我们将这个加入了噪音的图片输入到神经网络中。
And then we input that noised image into the neural network.
我们还输入时间步长，因为我们也要将时间嵌入进去。
We also put in the time step because we also care about adding that time embedding in.
然后神经网络预测噪音的输出。
And the neural network predicts the noise as output.
通过比较预测的噪音和我们实际加入的噪音，我们可以使用均方误差（MSE）计算损失。
Comparing that predicted noise with the noise that we actually added, we can compute the loss using mean squared error, MSE.
然后我们所要做的就是反向传播并学习。
And then all we have to do is back prop and learn.
这样，模型就会学习什么是噪音，什么是游戏角色了。
So the model will then learn what is noise and what is sprite.
好的，接下来我们来看我们训练用的 Notebook。
Cool, so on to our training notebook here.
这些都是之前的内容，只需按 Shift+Enter 键进行设置即可。
So this is all the same as before, just hitting shift enter, setting things up with the unit.
这里的训练超参数比较有趣，我们的批次大小是100，
Here what's interesting is, you know, our training hyperparameters, our batch size of 100,
我们将进行32个轮次的训练，还有我们的学习速率。
and we are going through 32 different epochs and our learning rate.
我将按 Shift + Enter 键来运行它。
I'm just going to shift enter there to run it.
这里的设置模型和噪音计划与之前相似。
Again, similar things here of setting up the model and the noise schedule for those scaling parameters.
现在开始训练。
Now here's where you get into training.
你可以加载你的数据集，我们将它加载到数据加载器中。
So you can load your data set, and we're loading it into that data loader here.
这是一个16x16的游戏角色数据集。
It's this 16 by 16 sprites data set.
我们也加载了优化器。
And we're also loading up our optimizer.
这里有一个函数，它会扰乱我们的输入，
And here's the function that perturbs our input, meaning that it takes the image,
意思是它会根据特定的时间步长向图像添加适当级别的噪音，并返回图像。
it adds the right noise level for that specific time step to that image, and returns it.
我可以在这里按 Shift + Enter 键。
So I can hit Shift+Enter here.
由于在 CPU 上进行训练需要很多小时，因此我们在这里实际上不会逐步进行训练，
So here we won't actually step through training because it takes many hours on CPU,
这也是这些 Notebook 托管的位置。
and that's where these notebooks are hosted.
但我非常建议你走一遍这个过程。
But I really recommend that you do go through this.
这就是我们刚刚一起看过的那段代码。
This is the exact code that we had just looked at together.
但我们可以做的是，我们确实训练了这个模型，并在不同的训练轮次中保存了模型，
But what we can do is that we did train this model and save the model at different epochs,
这样你就可以运行采样，并能够看到它在每个训练轮次中的表现。
such that you can then run sampling and be able to see how it does at each epoch.
这是你之前看到的相同的采样代码。
So this is, again, the same sampling code you saw before.
我会快速过一下。
I'm just going to breeze through that.
这里是你加载第零轮次的模型的地方。
And here is where you would load the model for epoch zero.
这是模型检查点的路径，第零轮次的模型。
So this is the path to that model checkpoint, model_0 for epoch zero.
我要加载这个模型。
I'm going to load that model.
然后你可以直接可视化这些样本。
And then here you can just visualize the samples.
再次运行之前相同的采样方法，这个方法在上一个视频中有讲解，叫做DDPM。
And, again, this is running the same sampling method as before called DDPM that you learned in the previous video.
这需要几分钟，我们将在视频中加快这个过程。
This takes a couple minutes, and we'll speed this up in the video.
非常好！
Great.
我们可以在这里点击播放。
So we can hit play here.
虽然还有点不清晰，但已经开始理解游戏角色的大致轮廓。
A bit amorphous still, but, you know, starting to understand the general outlines of sprites.
它并不是纯粹的噪音。
It's not pure noise.
我们也有第四轮的模型让你参考。
So we also have epoch four here for you to see.
你可以看到模型在改进，
So you can see the model improving.
这些看起来更像游戏角色了。
These look a little bit more like sprites.
接下来是第八轮。
And epoch eight.
再进一步，
A little bit more.
你可以看到里面有些书。
See some books in there, actually.
最后，这是第31轮，
And, finally, Epoch 31.
或者当我们从零开始计数时，可能实际上是第32轮。
Or this might actually be 32 when we index from zero.
这些看起来更像游戏角色图像了。
So these look a lot more like sprites.
你可以看到这里有一把剑。
You can see a sword here.
这可能是巫师帽。
This is probably the wizard hat.
这里有个药水。
See a potion here.
但当然，这里还有一些斑点，一些人物。
But, of course, there are still some blobs here and there, some people here.
它还不够完美，还可以继续优化。
So it's not perfect, and it could keep going.
在下一个视频中，你将可以控制你生成的内容，也就是你可以指定它生成物体或者这些人物。
So in the next video, you'll get to control what you generate, meaning you can tell it to generate objects or these people, for example.